Guide to the Gibbs Symposium Videorecordings
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Gibbs Symposium videorecordings
1989-1989
RU 115
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.5
(15 videotapes)
The materials consist of videorecordings of the Gibbs Symposium held at Yale in 1989. The symposium was held in honor of Josiah Willard Gibbs, a leader in theoretical physics.
Gibbs Symposium ( 1989 Yale University)
Arnolʹd, V. I. (Vladimir Igorevich), 1937-2010
Chandrasekhar, S. (Subrahmanyan), 1910-1995
Fefferman, Charles, 1949-
Fisher, Michael E. (Michael Ellis), 1931-
Fröhlich, Jürg
Jeanloz, R. (Raymond)
Klein, Martin J.
Langlands, Robert P., 1936-
Oppenheim, Irwin, 1929-2014
Polyakov, A. M.
Samuelson, Paul A. (Paul Anthony), 1915-2009
Schmidt, Benno C., 1942-
Stevens, Charles F., 1934-
Widom, B.
Wightman, A. S.
Yang, Chen Ning, 1922-
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 50 (YRG 50), Records of conferences and symposia at Yale.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of videorecordings of the Gibbs Symposium held at Yale in 1989. The symposium was held in honor of Josiah Willard Gibbs, a leader in theoretical physics.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by session.
Thermodynamics -- Congresses; Videotapes; Gibbs, J. Willard (Josiah Willard), 1839-1903 -- Congresses; Gibbs Symposium ( 1989 Yale University)
- Gibbs Symposium [videorecordings], 1989; Accession 1990-A-037
  - Benno C. Schmidt, Jr., President, Yale University, opening remarks, 1989 May 15; videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Martin J. Klein, Yale University, "Gibbs' Physics in Historical Context", 1989 May 15; videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Arthur Wightman, Princeton University, "On the Prescience Gibbs," videotapes (VHS), 1989 May 15 (Box 2)
  - Michael E. Fisher, University of Maryland, "Phases and Phase Diagrams," videotapes (VHS), 1989 May 15 (Box 3)
  - Robert P. Langlands, Institute for Advanced Study, "Pure Mathematics from the Mathematics of Physics: The Rise of representation Theory and its Role in Number Theory", 1989 May 15; videotape (VHS) (Box 4)
  - Jürg Fröhlich, ETH, Zurich, "Theory of Critical Points in Statistical Mechanics", 1989 May 15; videotape (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Irwin Oppenheim, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, "Ensembles vs. Assemblies and the Approach to Equilibrium", 1989 May 15; videotape (VHS) (Box 6)
  - B. Widom, Cornell University, "Two Ideas from Gibbs: The Entropy Inequality and the Dividing Surface", 1989 May 16; videotape (VHS) (Box 7)
  - C. Fefferman, Princeton University, "Rigorous Results on the Gibbs Ensemble for Coulomb Systems", 1989 May 16; videotape (VHS) (Box 8)
  - V.I. Arnold, Steklov Institute, Moscow, "Contact Geometry: The Geometrical Method of Gibbs' Thermodynamics" (part 1), 1989 May 16; videotape (VHS) (Box 8)
  - V.I. Arnold, Steklov Institute, Moscow, "Contact Geometry: The Geometrical Method of Gibbs' Thermodynamics" (part 2), 1989 May 16; videotape (VHS) (Box 9)
  - Raymond Jeanloz, University of California, Berkeley, "Innerspace: Earth's Deep Mangle and Core", 1989 May 16; videotape (VHS); Audio is distorted on the original recording. (Box 10)
  - Charles F. Stevens, Yale University, "Echoes of Gibbs in Contemporary Neurobiology", 1989 May 16; videotape (VHS) (Box 11)
  - A.M. Polyakov, Landau Institute, Moscow, "Statistical Mechanics of Random Surfaces", 1989 May 16; videotape (VHS) (Box 12)
  - S. Chandrasekhar, University of Chicago, "How One May Explore the Physical Content of General Relativity", 1989 May 17; videotape (VHS) (Box 13)
  - Paul Samuelson, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, "Gibbs in Economics", 1989 May 17; videotape (VHS) (Box 14)
  - C.N. Yang, State University of New York, Stony Brook, "Genesis of Maxwell's Equations", 1989 May 17; videotape (VHS) (Box 15)